<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Invited Talks | HD-BDM Lab</title>
    <link>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Invited Talks</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Invited Talks</title>
      <link>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professor Wang Xiaotian Delivers Keynote Speech at the Forum on Innovation in Psychological Science and Service to the Nation</title>
      <link>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/2025-08-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/2025-08-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 19–20, the Forum on Innovation in Psychological Science and Service to the Nation was successfully held in Jinan, Shandong. The forum was jointly organized by Acta Psychologica Sinica, Psychological Science, Advances in Psychological Science, and Psychological Exploration, co-sponsored by the Chinese Psychological Society, the CPC Pingyin County Committee of Jinan, and the People’s Government of Pingyin County, and hosted by the Pingyin County Bureau of Education and Sports together with Ruiyang Xinyu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the theme “Strengthening Innovation in Basic and Applied Psychological Research to Better Serve National Development”, the forum brought together leading experts and scholars in psychology from across China to discuss the discipline’s vital role in national strategies and social development.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/images/250826_2.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%;&#34; alt=&#34;Home Image&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
At the conference, Professor Wang Xiaotian was invited to deliver a keynote speech titled “AI vs. Human Rationality in Decision-Making: A Psychological Turing Test.” In his talk, Professor Wang compared artificial intelligence with human rational decision-making, introduced new perspectives on the concept of a “psychological Turing test,” and emphasized the critical role of psychology in uncovering the unique features of human thinking and value judgment.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/images/250826_3.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%;&#34; alt=&#34;Home Image&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
During the forum, Professor Wang was also interviewed by Jinan Daily. He urged society and parents to place greater importance on values education, encouraging curiosity over utilitarianism, and fostering an open and positive environment for the healthy growth of young people. He stressed that education is not only about knowledge and skills, but also about character development and long-term growth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professor Wang Xiaotian – Curiosity as a Guiding Principle The 10th Anniversary Interview Series of the Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen)</title>
      <link>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/2024-11-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/2024-11-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Professor Wang Xiaotian – Curiosity as a Guiding Principle: The 10th Anniversary Interview Series of the Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is reposted from the WeChat official account of the Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen)(&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/SJ80_9ioGFyajcG4k5lgVg%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/SJ80_9ioGFyajcG4k5lgVg)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time passes swiftly. In 2024, the Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences at The Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen) celebrates its 10th anniversary. In this moment of celebration, the faculty has launched a special series of interviews with key figures. Over the past decade, what changes and developments have taken place at the faculty? What are its goals and plans for the next decade? Let us follow the professors&amp;rsquo; footsteps as we reflect on the past and look to the future. In this issue, we are honored to invite Professor Wang Xiaotian to share his thoughts and insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;from-nothing-to-something-gradually-perfecting&#34;&gt;From Nothing to Something, Gradually Perfecting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Why did you choose to join the Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences at The Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen)?
A: I came to The Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen) in 2018. At that time, I was invited to establish a psychology program, which was very exciting for me. The unique positioning of the university attracted me, particularly its global vision, English-taught courses, focus on general education, and emphasis on cultural cultivation. I believe that very few universities in China can fully implement these four aspects, and The Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen) does this exceptionally well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among research universities in China, our school stands out with vast potential. Recognizing this educational philosophy, I decided to join the Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences, with the initial goal of creating a psychology program grounded in China but with an international perspective. Since then, as the founding department head, my colleagues and I have worked together to successfully establish an integrated psychology curriculum at the undergraduate, master&amp;rsquo;s, and doctoral levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: During your time here, what significant developments and changes have you observed in the faculty over the past ten years? What distinctive features and advantages do you think the Applied Psychology program at the Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences has?
A: Over the past ten years, the faculty has undergone a significant transformation from nothing to something, which I consider the most important milestone. I believe that an excellent university should cultivate three key abilities in students: scientific methods, critical thinking, and independent character. The purpose of university education is to provide a space for young people to grow, allowing them to enrich themselves and find themselves before entering society. We aim to cultivate not just &amp;ldquo;knowledgeable&amp;rdquo; individuals, but intellectuals with deep cultural foundation and independent character. In the era of big data, acquiring information has become easy, but true scholarship lies in understanding and applying this knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe our undergraduates are excellent, with a high overall quality. The Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences provides the entire university with English-taught courses and general education, both of which hold a significant place in our university culture. Our Applied Psychology courses are framed around holistic development, covering fields like developmental psychology, educational psychology, and career development, with an emphasis on cultural heritage and the integration of liberal arts and sciences. In terms of curriculum design, we focus on the integration of theory and practice. Students are required not only to complete core courses but also to participate in experimental papers, lab activities, community projects, or internships at schools. In the past five years, we have established about nine labs, including the Child Behavior Observation Lab, Cognitive and Behavioral Research Lab, Virtual Reality Lab, Near-Infrared Spectroscopy Imaging Lab, and Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation Lab. These labs have provided rich research opportunities for various research teams. These developments have made our academic foundation more solid and provided students with broader practical platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: What aspects of the faculty have left a strong impression on you since you joined?
A: The continuous development of the faculty excites me greatly. As a teacher, it is a privilege to work with young students. Their energy and intellectual challenges constantly inspire me, prompting me to engage in self-learning while building a relationship of mutual teaching and learning with them. As teachers, we need to learn from the masters, from our colleagues, and from our students, continually enriching and perfecting ourselves. Our role is not only to impart knowledge but also to help students grow, becoming their mentors and friends, and ultimately fostering a cooperative relationship. I am particularly impressed by the students I have taught. Their excellence and humility give me great satisfaction. For instance, one student sent me an email before studying abroad in the U.S., thanking me for my guidance, without mentioning her acceptance into Harvard University. Another student, studying in the UK, mentioned how the democratic atmosphere at our school had been instrumental in his development. These small details have deeply reminded me of the importance of leading by example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;maintaining-curiosity-focusing-on-passion&#34;&gt;Maintaining Curiosity, Focusing on Passion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: Over the past nine years, has your teaching philosophy changed as your experience has grown?
A: Over the past nine years, I have accumulated many insights in teaching and work. My teaching philosophy follows Confucius&amp;rsquo;s idea of &amp;ldquo;teaching without discrimination,&amp;rdquo; which has profound implications in the education field: education should not tolerate any form of discrimination, ensuring every student has equal access to educational opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In specific teaching practices, my philosophy is simpler: &amp;ldquo;Let curiosity guide you throughout.&amp;rdquo; Why is curiosity so important? Because it helps us overcome utilitarianism, thereby reducing anxiety and pressure from competition. Guided by curiosity, we can learn how to become experts in our fields. According to the &amp;ldquo;10,000-hour rule,&amp;rdquo; if you devote enough time and effort, you can become an expert. However, even after becoming an expert, we must continue to move forward with curiosity, expanding our vision and collaboration skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: You have extensive experience in interdisciplinary research. What importance do you think communication between different disciplines has for research innovation?
A: Personally, I transitioned from medicine to psychology, driven by curiosity. By exploring knowledge from multiple disciplines, I discovered my passion for psychology. This interdisciplinary interest was not deliberate but a natural result. The definitions of different disciplines are often external, but our interests and curiosity should not be limited by them. For example, someone researching AI might realize the importance of psychology in application design and data processing and thus begin to incorporate psychology into their work. Similarly, people with a humanities background can create new research perspectives by combining psychology with anthropology or sociology. While interdisciplinary integration may not immediately yield significant results, it can bring long-term benefits. My medical background allows me to quickly catch up in fields like biopsychology and neuroscience, which helps me better understand and address real-world issues. However, as we grow older, we often fall into the &amp;ldquo;adult trap,&amp;rdquo; where initial enthusiasm and goals are replaced by mere financial gain, and work becomes driven by its rewards. This shift can cause us to lose interest in our work. Successful businesses thrive by loving their products and striving for excellence, which ultimately leads to profit. Therefore, interdisciplinary work should not be pursued for its own sake but because curiosity keeps us focused on refining our own field and passions, guiding us to explore and grow within complex knowledge systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: What advice do you have for students conducting social science research?
A: For students doing social science research, my advice is to approach it with curiosity, following your inner feelings. At the same time, it is crucial to maintain a calm mindset. History teaches us that it is not heroes who create the times, but the times that create heroes. Therefore, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry too much about whether you can change the world. Instead, focus on doing what you love in the ordinary moments and prepare yourself for the right opportunities. To do this, first lower your utilitarian mindset. Through continuous learning, cultivate the habit of lifelong learning. Students should focus on one or two fields, digging deep and making long-term investments to become experts. Additionally, patience with solitude is key. Students need to maintain interest in their research, enjoying the process rather than being distracted by external temptations. Today, technologies like AI and virtual reality are highly attractive, but becoming immersed in the virtual world can weaken our focus and motivation and even affect our social interactions. Therefore, cultivating self-discipline is essential. Students should learn to find useful information for themselves and relax at appropriate times, but avoid indulgence—learn to relax without overindulging. In short, maintaining curiosity, a calm mindset, and self-discipline will help you progress further on the road to personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;taking-the-best-from-each-discipline&#34;&gt;Taking the Best from Each Discipline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: How do you view the impact of emerging technologies (such as AI) on psychology research and applications?
A: Emerging technologies, especially AI and genetic technology, are rapidly changing our world. The development of these technologies is human-centered, and understanding humanity is the foundation for effectively applying these technologies. AI&amp;rsquo;s characteristic is that it &amp;ldquo;knows others but not itself,&amp;rdquo; lacking self-awareness, which means we need to explore how to interact effectively and beneficially with this emerging intelligence. AI brings convenience but also generates much uncertainty. In this consumer era, society encourages innovation, but it also heightens anxiety about the future. With rapid technological development, many traditional enterprises face the risk of being eliminated, leading to increased anxiety. This uncertainty, in turn, makes psychology an increasingly important discipline, helping people cope with anxiety and change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the application of psychology must be based on an in-depth understanding of human behavior. Whether in experimental economics in finance or behavioral big data analysis, the integration of psychology with these fast-developing fields is crucial. We are in an era that requires &amp;ldquo;collaboration between the left and right brain,&amp;rdquo; with AI considered the &amp;ldquo;third brain&amp;rdquo; in information processing and feedback, playing an important role and introducing new challenges, such as how to filter and process information overload. As these new technologies develop, the value of psychology will become even more prominent. If humanity can master these technologies without being overwhelmed by them, we can guide their development and avoid the risks that come with them.
Therefore, psychology must continuously evolve to keep pace with these changes, combining emerging technologies with deep understanding of human behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professor Wang Invited to Deliver Keynote on “Behavioral Decision-Making in the AI Era” at the National Decision Psychology Teaching Materials Symposium</title>
      <link>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/2024-10-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/2024-10-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From October 25 to 26, 2024, the Chinese Psychological Society’s Decision Psychology Committee hosted the National Symposium on Teaching Materials for Decision Psychology and the 2nd Doctoral Forum on “Decision-Making Behavior” in Guangzhou, Guangdong. As an expert in behavioral decision research, Professor Wang was invited to deliver a keynote address titled “Behavioral Decision-Making in the AI Era,” which drew significant interest and enthusiastic responses from attendees.
In his presentation, Professor Wang delved into the profound impact of artificial intelligence (AI) technology on human decision-making behaviors, examining the opportunities and challenges brought by AI. He highlighted that as AI technology advances rapidly, research in decision psychology will increasingly become embedded in everyday life and society, broadening its practical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/images/pic5.png&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%;&#34; alt=&#34;Home Image&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Professor Wang emphasized that in an era of rapid AI development, researchers must not only acquire new analytical tools and methods but also adapt and refine their own decision-making abilities to keep pace with future changes. 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/images/pic6.png&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%;&#34; alt=&#34;Home Image&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Finally, he offered doctoral students and researchers valuable advice—delivered with humor—on enhancing personal self-management in a highly intelligent environment.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/images/pic7.png&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%;&#34; alt=&#34;Home Image&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Professor Wang’s presentation provided attendees with new perspectives for future research and called on the academic community to explore the deeper impact of AI on human behavior and decision-making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#34;Acta Psychologica Sinica&#34; Forum invites Professor Wang Xiaotian to explore the challenges and opportunities of psychology in the AI era.</title>
      <link>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/2024-04-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/2024-04-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acta Psychologica Sinica&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly advancing artificial intelligence (AI) technology, human society is facing unprecedented challenges and opportunities. The &amp;ldquo;Looking Forward to the Future&amp;rdquo; series of forums initiated by the top domestic journal Acta Psychologica Sinica successfully held an online academic lecture on the evening of April 28, 2024. Professor Wang was invited to be the keynote speaker. The theme was &amp;ldquo;AI Uncertainty and Psychology in the Information Age.&amp;rdquo; The lecture was chaired by Professor Fu Xiaolan, editor-in-chief of Acta Psychologica Sinica and director of the Institute of Psychology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, who also interacted with the live audience in a discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eyhxg.xetslk.com/sl/3vGUA0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lecture replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the lecture, Professor Wang first discussed the characteristics of the AI era, including the contradiction between massive information and human cognitive limitations, the limitations of high uncertainty and probability, the arrogance of rationality, and the limitations of scientific thinking, and the contradiction between technological progress and evolutionary design. He emphasized that psychology plays a crucial role in understanding and managing AI. Intelligent management of AI requires not only a deep understanding of AI itself but also an understanding of the differences between AI and human rationality. Professor Wang shared the empirical research results of his recent study on risk decision-making between ChatGPT and humans, and discussed in detail the similarities and differences between AI and humans in risk decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Fu highly praised Professor Wang&amp;rsquo;s report and hosted a lively interactive discussion with over five thousand online audience members, further enriching the content of the lecture and providing multidimensional analysis and thinking for the intersection and integration of psychology and AI.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/images/pic4.png&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%;&#34; alt=&#34;Home Image&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The series of lectures hosted by Acta Psychologica Sinica provides an academic platform for the discussion of AI uncertainty in the field of psychology. Professor Wang&amp;rsquo;s insights provide valuable ideas for psychologists and practitioners, which will help promote the innovation and development of Chinese psychology in the AI era.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professor Wang Delivers Invited Talk at the &#34;Century of Hundred Psychologists&#34; Lecture Series in China</title>
      <link>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/psy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/psy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the afternoon of April 13, 2024, Professor Wang was invited to present a special talk titled &amp;ldquo;Psychology: Integration and Intersection—My Interdisciplinary and Original Research&amp;rdquo; at the &amp;ldquo;Century of Hundred Psychologists&amp;rdquo; lecture series in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series of lectures is organized by Guangxi Normal University, with the Education Department of the same university taking charge of the execution, and has received significant support and assistance from the Guangxi Normal University Press and the Guangxi Psychological Society. The aim of these lectures is to invite distinguished psychologists recognized by the Chinese Psychological Society to share their landmark achievements in the field of psychological research and discuss their academic growth and scholarly insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the lecture, Professor Wang reviewed his academic journey, including the rich empirical experience he accumulated in both basic and applied research, and provided a perspective on the future development of the discipline. He particularly highlighted several important lines of his research, including the AA hypothesis of decisions biases,the Tri-reference point theory, the Signaling Hypothesis of Blood glucose and the Adaptive Life-span Management theory.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/images/pic3.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%;&#34; alt=&#34;Home Image&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The lecture was concluded with a summary by Professor Zhang Jijia. Professor Zhang emphasized that Professor Wang was also among the first to introduce evolutionary theory into the study of behavioral decision-making, contributing significantly to the dissemination of evolutionary psychology in China. Professor Zhang also specifically mentioned four valuable experiences in academic research: firstly, a solid disciplinary foundation is a prerequisite for integration and interdisciplinary research; secondly, profound humanistic care is an indispensable motivation for studying human behavior; thirdly, engaging in interdisciplinary and integrative research can promote academic innovation; and lastly, maintaining a sustained interest and attention to theory is key to exploring the deep-seated causes of human behavior.
Professor Wang’s talk not only showcased his profound expertise in the field of psychology and his innovative spirit in interdisciplinary research but also provided attendees with new perspectives for understanding and exploring human decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professor Wang Xiaotian Invited by Dragon Television (东方卫视) to Participate in the Recording of Financial Insights Program</title>
      <link>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/east/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article is sourced from the official WeChat account of 第一财经.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The Dragon TV program &amp;ldquo;Financial Insights&amp;rdquo; invited Professor Wang Xiaotian, Director of the Applied Psychology Program at the School of Humanities and Social Sciences, Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen), to share insights on the anchoring effect in behavioral finance with the audience. The episode aired on October 23, 2023, at 10:45 PM.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/images/pic2.png&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%;&#34; alt=&#34;Home Image&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Whether you are hesitating to buy a high-priced item on sale in a store or feeling the urge to buy a stock when it falls below your set psychological price level in the stock market, there is a common and powerful psychological phenomenon at play: the anchoring effect. It pervades our daily lives, shopping decisions, and investment behaviors. Why can the original price tag of a product attract purchases? Why do investors make irrational decisions anchored to a stock&amp;rsquo;s historical price? How can one identify and counteract this bias? This episode will reveal to you that the first number you hear can become your decision-making &amp;ldquo;anchor,&amp;rdquo; but it may not necessarily be the most rational choice.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cuhko365-my.sharepoint.com/%e2%9c%8c%ef%b8%8f/g/personal/xtwang_cuhk_edu_cn/EZnQKyjn7aJIsr8WsTKNJlgBl_kiyfp48SkPoXjTq2AwIg?e=GRi8ea&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Program Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professor Wang Xiaotian Invited to Deliver Keynote Speech at the 25th National Academic Conference of Psychology</title>
      <link>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/2023-10-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hd-bdm-lab.netlify.app/invited_talks/2023-10-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article is sourced from the official WeChat account of the School of Humanities and Social Sciences at the Chinese University of Hong Kong, Shenzhen.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The 25th National Psychology Conference opened on October 13, 2023, at Sichuan Normal University in Chengdu, Sichuan. The conference, spanning three days, featured a keynote speech by Professor Wang Xiaotian on October 14, titled &amp;ldquo;Between Life and Death: Intertemporal Decision-Making within the Framework of Life History Theory&amp;rdquo; (Conference Announcement: &lt;a href=&#34;http://nacp2023.psysoc.org.cn/%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://nacp2023.psysoc.org.cn/)&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract-of-the-speech&#34;&gt;Abstract of the Speech&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most economic and psychological theories share two common assumptions: the finiteness of time and the finiteness of resources. Our series of studies explore how the finiteness of time, or rather, the finiteness of life, shapes human behavior. Each individual&amp;rsquo;s interaction with time occurs within the brief or extended span of a lifetime, making it essential for psychology to focus on life histories and life history theories. Unlike other animals, human beings possess autonoetic consciousness, enabling them to consciously plan their lives within the limited time they have and make decisions accordingly. One&amp;rsquo;s worldview, encompassing their perception of time and values, is influenced not only by the perception of time but also by how they perceive and respond to two fundamental aspects of life: the inevitability of death and the uncertainty/impermanence of death. In this presentation, I will demonstrate how adjusting the inevitability and uncertainty of death within the framework of life history can impact individuals or populations&amp;rsquo; delay discounting (future discounting). I will also discuss how we use meta-analysis to compare different developmental psychological theories, generate age curves for delay discounting across the entire life history from 178 samples, and present our current research progress and related reflections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cuhko365-my.sharepoint.com/%e2%9c%8c%ef%b8%8f/g/personal/xtwang_cuhk_edu_cn/ET9gGd8YmbtFlOXw-zfsUQABIna2GV0QyC3pjumymIzK9A?e=7cOBbe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Speech Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
